###################################

To add new translations or change existing ones, open the Lang folder and translate any of the files. 
If it's a new translation, rename the translated file and place it in the Lang folder. 
Reload the script (option in menu) and you'll find it in the menu under Languages.

en.xml contains the text in the windows and menu. You only need to change what is inside the caption, titlebar, help, defaulttext, and string tags (in other words, don't change the Id attributes).
Replace author with your own name/alias and email if you'd like it to appear in the About window.

Words in ALL_CAPS do not need to be translated (as these will be replaced by their respective variables), but should be placed in gramatically correct locations. Also ignore the &#10; These indicate new lines.

New translations WILL NOT BE DELETED when updating/reinstalling this script
If I've added a translation to the script that uses the same filename as yours, it WILL BE OVERWRITTEN
But if it's the same filename, it's probably the same translation anyway.

###################################

To add or remove Pokemon from the random selection, open RandMon.js and follow the existing format.
If you change the number of Pokemon in the list (default 649), be sure to change the number in the second line, as well to match the new number of Pokemon.

switch(Math.ceil(rand()*649)){

is the default second line.

THIS FILE WILL BE OVERWRITTEN WHEN UPDATING/REINSTALLING THIS SCRIPT
TO SAVE YOUR CHANGES, COPY THIS FILE TO THE SOMEWHERE ELSE ON YOUR COMPUTER BEFORE UPDATING

###################################

To add custom types for Pokemon, open TypeList.js and follow the existing format.
It's probably best to add new case statements right below the second line. 
Types are numbered. For a list of types, open the Lang folder, select an xml file, and scroll to the bottom to find them listed.

Adding names to these files is not the same as creating custom Mons via the interface (or editing the MonParty.ini file).

THIS FILE WILL BE OVERWRITTEN WHEN UPDATING/REINSTALLING THIS SCRIPT
TO SAVE YOUR CHANGES, COPY THIS FILE TO THE SOMEWHERE ELSE ON YOUR COMPUTER BEFORE UPDATING

###################################

To add new types, add in each of the lang .xml files the name of the type (types are listed at the bottom), along with a new Id for each (if it's the first custom type, make it 17)
To display the type the same in all languages, use the same string each time

Next add to aTypeMatchup in Vars.js
[1,1,1,1,1,1,1,1,1,1,1,1,1,1,1,1,1]
There are 17 1s in the line above for each of the 17 default types
Next add one more ",1" to EVERY line in aTypeMatchup, including the one you just added
(if there are now 18 types (default 17 + 1 custom) there should be 18 numbers in each row,
 if there are now 19 types (default 17 + 2 custom) there should be 19 numbers in each row...)
Be sure the line above the last type ends in a comma

The 1 means that it is a 1x type modifier while defending
(Row 16 (steel), Column 1 (normal) means normal attacks do 0.5x damage to steel types)
To change the type matchups, change the numbers

(in the end, it should make an (number of types) x (number of types) grid
This is how the type affects other types
For a more graphical view of how the default 17 are arranged, visit 
http://pokemondb.net/type

Custom types will now be integrated into all aspects of the script without further configuration

THIS FILE WILL BE OVERWRITTEN WHEN UPDATING/REINSTALLING THIS SCRIPT
TO SAVE YOUR CHANGES, COPY THIS FILE TO THE SOMEWHERE ELSE ON YOUR COMPUTER BEFORE UPDATING
NEW LANGUAGES MAY BE ADDED DURING SCRIPT UPDATES -- RECONFIGURE YOUR CUSTOM TYPING AFTER

There's no GUI to do this because I don't like making them and found this one particularly complicated kkk

###################################